This is Berk
It's 12 days North of hopeless and a few degrees South of freezing to death.
It's located solidly on the Meridian of Misery.
My village. In a word: sturdy.
It's been here for seven generations but every single building is new.
We have fishing, hunting, and a charming view of the sunsets.
The only problems are the pests.
You see, most places have mice or mosquitoes.
We have...
Dragons.
Most people would leave, but not us.
We're Vikings.
We stubbornness issues.
My name is Hiccup.
Great name, I know. But it's not the worst.
Parents believe a hideous name will frighten off Gnomes and Trolls.
Like our charming Viking demeanor wouldn't do that.
'Morning.
What are you doing here? Get inside!
Get back inside!
Hiccup! What is he doing out again... What are you doing out? Get inside!
That's Stoick the Vast, Chief of the tribe.
They say that when he was a baby he popped a Dragon's head clean off its shoulders.
Do I believe it? Yes, I do.
What have we got?
Gronckles, Nadders, Zipplebacks... Oh, and hordes of Monstruous Nightmares.
Any Night Furys?
None so far.   Good.
Light the torches!
Oh, nice of you to join the party. I thought you'd been carried off.
Who? Me? Nah, come on... I'm way too muscular for their taste.
They wouldn't know what to do with all... this.
Well, they need toothpicks, don't they?
The meathead with the attitude and interchangeable hands, is Gobber.
I have been his apprentice ever since I was little.
Well, littler
We move to the moor defenses. We'll counterattack with the catapults.
See? Old village. Lots and lots of new houses.
Fire!
Oh, and that's Fishlegs
Snotlout
The twins, Ruffnut and Tuffnut...
And...
Astrid.
Aww, their job is so much cooler.
Oh, come on. Let me out, please. I need to make my mark!
Oh, you have made plenty of marks. All in the wrong places.
Please, 2 minutes. I'll kill a dragon. My life will get infinitely better.
I might even get a date.
You can't lift a hammer. You can't swing an axe.
You can't even throw one of these.
Okay, fine, but this will throw it for me.
See, now this right here is what I'm talking about.
But it... it's a mild calibration issue.
Hiccup, if you ever want to get out there to fight dragons
you need to stop all....
this.
But you just pointed to all of me.
Yes, that's it.
Stop being all of you.
Oh...   Oh, yes.
You sir, are playing a dangerous game...
keeping this much raw Vikingness contained.
There will be consequences!   I take my chances.
Sword, sharpened, now!
One day I'll get out there.
Because killing a dragon is everything around here.
A Nadderhead is sure to get me at least noticed.
Gronckles are tough.
Taking down one of those would definitely get me a girlfriend.
A Zippleback: ...
exotic, two heads, twice the status.
They found the sheep!
Concentrate fire over the lower bank!
Hurry up!
Fire!
And then, there's the Monstruous Nightmare.
Only the best Vikings go after those.
They have this nasty habit of setting themselves on fire.
Reload!
I'll take care of this.
But the ultimate prize is the dragon no one's ever seen.
We call it the...
Night Fury!   Get down!
Jump!
This thing never steals food, never shows itself, and...
never misses.
No one has ever killed a Night Fury.
That's why I'm going to be the first.
Mind the fort, Hiccup. They need me out there.
Stay! Put!
There.
You know what I mean.
Hiccup, what are you doing?   Come back here!
Yeah, I know, Be right back!
Mind yourself!
The devils still have some juice in them.
Come on.
Give me something to shoot at. Give me something to shoot at.
Oh! I hit it? Yes, I hit it!
Did anybody see that?
Except for you.
Do not let them escape!   Right!
You're all out.
Oh, and there's one more thing you need to know...
Sorry, Dad.
Okay, but I hit a Night Fury.
It's not like the last few times, Dad!
I mean, I really actually hit...
You guys were busy and I had a very clear shot.
It went down just off Raven Point. Let's get a search party out there before...
Stop!
Just, stop!
Every time you step outside disaster falls.
Can you not see that I have bigger problems?
Winter is almost here and I have an entire village to feed!
Between you and me, the village could do with a little less feeding, don't you think?
This isn't a joke, Hiccup!
Why can't you follow the simplest orders?
I, I can't stop myself. I see a dragon and I have to just...
kill it. You know, it's who I am, Dad.
Oh, you are many things, Hiccup, but a dragon killer is not one of them.
Get back to the house. Make sure he gets there.
I have his mess to clean up.
Quite the performance.
I've never seen any one mess up that badly. That helped!
Thank you. Thank you. I was trying.
I really did hit one.   Sure, Hiccup.
He never listens.   Well, it runs in the family.
And when he does, it's always with this disappointed scowl
like someone skimped on the meat in his sandwich.
Excuse me, barmaid. I'm afraid you brought me the wrong offspring.
I ordered an extra large boy with beefy arms. Extra guts and glory on the side.
This here. This is a talking fish bone!
Now, you're thinking about this all wrong.
It's not so much what you look like. It's what's inside that he can't stand.
Thank you for summing that up.
Look, the point is, stop trying so hard to be something you're not.
I just want to be one of you guys.
Either we face them or they'll finish us.
It's the only way we'll be rid of them.
If we find the nest and destroy it, the dragons will leave.
They'll find another home.
One more search, before the ice sets in.
Those ships never come back.
We're Vikings. It's an occupational hazard.
Now who's with me?
Alright... Those who stay will look after Hiccup.
I'll pack my undies.
No, I need you to stay, and train some new recruits.
Oh, perfect, yeah. And while I'm busy Hiccup can cover the store.
Molten steel, razor sharp blades, lots of time to himself...
What could possibly go wrong?
Oh, what am I going to do with him, Gobber?
Put him in training with the others.
No, I'm serious.   So am I.
He'd be killed before you let the first dragon out of its cage.
Oh, you don't know that.   I do know that.
不 你不了解   我了解
No， you don't   No, actually, I do.
No, you don't.   Listen, you know what he's like.
From the time he could crawl he's been... different.
He doesn't listen. He has the attention span of a sparrow.
I take him fishing and he goes hunting for... for Trolls!
Trolls exist! They steal your socks.
But only the left ones. What's with that?
When I was a boy...   Oh, here we go.
My father told me to bang my head against a rock, and I did it.
I thought it was crazy, but I didn't question him.
And you know what happened?
You got a headache.   That rock split in two.
It taught me what a Viking could do, Gobber.
He could crush mountains, level forests,
tame seas!
Even as a boy I knew what I was, what I had to become...
Hiccup is not that boy.
You can't stop him, Stoick. You can only prepare him.
I know it seems hopeless, but the truth is you won't always be around to protect him.
He's going to get out there again. He's probably out there now.
Oh, the Gods hate me.
Some people lose their knife or their mug.
No, not me! I managed to lose an entire dragon.
Ow!
Oh, wow? I... I did it? Oh, I did it!
This fixes everything. Yes!
I have brought down this mighty beast!
I'm gonna kill you, dragon.
I'm gonna... I'm gonna cut out your heart and take it to my father.
I'm a Viking.
I'm a Viking!
I did this.
Hiccup.
Dad? Uh...
I have to talk to you, Dad.   I need to speak with you too, son.
I think it's time you to learned to fight dragons.   I don't want to fight dragons.
What?   What?
Uh, you go first.   No, no, you go first.
All right. You got your wish.
Dragon training. You start in the morning.
Oh man, I should have gone first.
Uh, cause I was thinking. You know, we have a surplus of dragon fighting Vikings but...
do we have enough breadmaking Vikings, or small home repair Vikings...
You'll need this.   I don't want to fight dragons.
Oh come on, yes you do.   Rephrase. Dad, I can't kill dragons.
But you will kill dragons.
No, I'm really very extra sure that I won't.
It's time, Hiccup.   Can you not hear me?
This is serious, son.
When you carry this axe, you carry all of us with you.
Which means: You walk like us. You talk like us. You think like us.
No more of... this.   You just gestured to all of me.
Deal?   This conversation is feeling very onesided.
Deal?
Deal.
Good.
Train hard.
I'll be back. Probably.
And I'll be here, maybe.
Welcome to dragon training.
No turning back.
I hope I get some serious burns.
I'm hoping for some mauling, like on my shoulder or lower back.
Yeah, it's only fun if you get a scar out of it.
Yeah, no kidding, right? Pain, love it.
Oh, great, who let him in?
Lets get started. The recruit who does best,
will win the honor of killing his first dragon in front of the entire village.
Hiccup already killed a Night Fury, so does that disqualify him or...?
Can I transfer to the class with the cool Vikings?
Don't worry. You're small and you're weak, That will make you a less of a target.
They'll see you as sick or insane and go after the more Vikinglike teens instead.
Behind these doors are just a few of the
many species you will learn to fight.
The Deadly Nadder.   Speed: 8, Armor: 16.
The Hideous Zippleback.   11 Stealth times two.
The Monstrous Nightmare.   Fire Power: 15.
The Terrible Terror.   Attack: 8, Venom: 12.
Can you stop that!
And the Gronckle.   Jaw Strength: 8.
Woah, woah, wait, aren't you going to teach us first?
I believe in learning on the job.
Today is about survival. If you get blasted, you're dead.
Quick! What's the first thing you're going to need?
A doctor?   + 5 Speed?
A shield?   Shield. Go.
Your most important piece of equipment is your shield.
If you must make a choice between a sword or a shield.
Take the shield.
Get your hands off my shield.   There's like a million shields.
Take that one. It has a flower on it. Girls like flowers.
Oops, now this one has blood on it.
Tuffnut, Ruffnut, your out.
What?   What?
Those shields are good for another thing. Noise.
Make lots of it and throw off a dragon's aim.
All dragons have a limited number of shots.
How many does a Gronckle have?
Five?   No, six.
Right, six. Thats one for each of you.
Fishlegs, out.
Hiccup, get in there!
So anyway, I moved into my parent's basement?
You should come by sometimes to work out, You look like you work out.
Snotlout, your done.
So I guess it's just you and me.   Nope, just you.
One shot left.
Hiccup!
And that's 6. Go back to bed you overgrown sausage.
You'll get another chance. Don't you worry.
Remember, a dragon will always...
always go for the kill.
So why didn't you?
Well this was stupid.
Why don't you just fly away?
Alright, where did Astrid go wrong in the ring today?
I mistimed my sommersault dive. It was sloppy. It threw off my reverse tumble.
Yeah, we noticed.   No, no you were great. That was so Astrid.
She's right. You have to be tough on yourselves. Where did Hiccup go wrong?
Uh, he showed up?   He didn't get eaten.
He's never where he should be.
Thank you, Astrid. You need to live and breathe this stuff.
The Dragon Manual... Everything we know about every dragon we know of.
No attacks tonight. Hurry up.
Wait? You mean read?   While we're still alive?
Why read words when you can just kill the stuff the words tell you stuff about?
Oh, I've read it like 7 times.
There's this water dragon that sprays boiling water at your face
and there's this other one that buries itself for like a week...
Yeah, sounds great. There was a chance I was going to read that.
But now...
You guys read, I'll go kill something.
Hey!
So I guess we'll share?   Read it.
All mine then? Wow. So, okay. I'll see you uh... tomorrow.
Dragon Classifications
Strike Class, Fear Class, Mystery Class.
Thunder Drum. This reclusive dragon inhabits sea caves and dark tide pools.
When startled, the Thunder Drum produces a concussive sound that can kill a man at close range.
Extremely dangerous. Kill on sight.
Timberjack: This gigantic creature has razorsharp wings that can slice through fullgrown trees.
Skulldren: Sprays scalding water on its victim. Extremely dangerous...
Changeling: Even newly hatch dragons can spray acid. Kill on sight.
Gronckle, Zippleback, The Skrill,
Boneknapper, Whispering Death.
Burns its victims. Buries its victims. Chokes its victims.
Turns victims inside out.
Extremely dangerous... Extremely dangerous...
Kill on sight... Kill on sight... Kill on sight...
Night Fury: Speed unknown. Size unknown.
The unholy offspring of lightning and death itself.
Never engage this dragon.
Your only chance: Hide and pray it does not find you.
I can almost smell them. They're close.
Steady.
Take us in.   Hard to port.
The Hell Hounds gate.
Hard to port.
Hey, you know, I just happened to notice, the book had nothing on Night Furys.
Is there like another book? or a sequel? Maybe a little Night Fury pamphlet?
Focus Hiccup! You're not even trying.
Today is all about attack!
Nadder's are quick and light on their feet. You be quicker and lighter.
I'm really beginning to question your teaching methods.
Look for its blind spot. Every dragon has one.
Find it. Hide in it, and strike.
Do you ever bathe?   You don't like it, then just get your own blind spot.
How about I give you one?
Blind spot, yes. Death spot, notsomuch.
Hey, hey, so how would one sneak up on a Night Fury?
No one's ever met one, and lived to tell the tale. Now, get in there!
I know, I know but hypothetically...
Watch out, babe, I'll take care of this.
The sun was in my eyes, Astrid.
What do you want me to do? Block out the sun?
I can do that. I don't have time right now.
Has anyone ever seen one napping?   Hiccup!
Hiccup!
Love on the battlefield.   She could do better.
L... Let me... why don't you...
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Well done, Astrid.
Is this some kind of a joke to you?
Our parent's war is about to become ours. Figure out which side your on.
Huh? Toothless.
I could of sworn you have...
teeth.
Uh, uh... no, no... no...
I... I don't have anymore.
And with one twist, he took my hand and swallowed it whole.
And I saw the look in his face. I was delicious.
He must have passed the word, because it wasn't a month
before another one of them took my leg.
Isn't it weird to think that your hand was inside a dragon?
Like, if your mind was still in control of it, you could have killed the dragon from the inside
by crushing his heart or something.
I swear, I'm so angry right now.
I'll avenge your beautiful hand and your beautiful foot.
I'll chop of the legs of every dragon I fight... with my face!
No. It's the wings and the tails you really want.
If it can't fly, it can't get away.
A downed dragon is a dead dragon.
Yeah.   Yeah.
Alright, I'm off to bed.
You should be too. Tomorrow we get to the big boys.
Slowly but surely, making our way up to Monstruous Nightmare.
But who'll win the honor of killing it?   It's gonna be me. It's my destiny. See?
Your mom let you get a tattoo?   It's not a tattoo. It's a birth mark.
Okay, I've been stuck with you since birth and that was never there before.
Yes, it was. You've just never seen me to the left side until now.
Hey, Toothless. I brought breakfast.
I hope... I hope you're hungry.
Okay, that's disgusting.
I got some salmon, some nice Icelandic cod, and a whole smoked eel.
No, no, no, no... no... Okay.
Yeah, I don't really like eel much either.
That's it. That's the good stuff. Aah, don't you mind me.
I'll just be back here, minding my own business.
It's okay...
Okay, okay...
Okay, that's not too bad. It works.
No, no, no, no, no, no...!
Oh my... It's working!
Yes, yes, I did it.
Today, is about teamwork.
Now, a wet dragon head can't light its fire.
The Hideous Zippleback is extra tricky.
One head breathes gas. The other head lights it.
Your job is to know which is which.
Razorsharp serrated teeth, and injects venom for predigestion.
Prefers ambush attack, crushing its victims.
Will you please stop that?!
If that dragon shows either of his faces, I'm gonna...
There!
Hey, it's us, idiots!
Your butts are getting bigger we thought you were a dragon.
Not that there's anything wrong with a dragonass fig...
Wait...
Oh! Oh, I'm hurt! I am very much hurt!
Chances of survival are dwindling into single digits now.
Oh! Wrong head.
Fishlegs!
Now Hiccup!
Aww, come on...
Hiccup!
Back, back, back!
Now don't you make me tell you again!
Yes, that's right. Back into your cage!
Now think about what you've done.
Okay, sooo, were we done?
'Cause I have some things I need to uh... Yep, I'll see you tomorrow.
Hey!
What was that?   How did you do that?
I left my axe back in the ring. You guys go on ahead.
I'll catch up with you.
Meet the Terrible Terror.
Ha! It's like the size of my...
Oooh! Get it off!
Oh, I'm hurt! I am very much hurt!
Wow! He's better than you ever were.
What?
Ooh, great.
Hiccup.
Hiccup? Are you in there?
Astrid, hey. Hi, Astrid. Hi Astrid. Hi Astrid
I normally don't care what people do, but you're acting weird.
Well, weirder.
Well, I trust you found the nest at least?
Not even close.
Excellent.
I hope you had a little more success than me.
Well, if by success, you mean that your parenting troubles are over with...
then, yes.
Congratulations Stoick! Everyone is so relieved.
Out with the old, and in with the new, right?
No one will miss that old nuisance.
The village is throwing a party to celebrate.
He's gone?
Um, yeah, most afternoons, but who can blame him?
I mean, the life of a celebrity is very rough.
He can barely walk through the village without being swarmed by his new fans.
Hiccup?   Who would have thought it, eh?
He has this way with the beasts.
Okay there, bud, were gonna take this nice and slow.
Here we go. Here we go. Position three, no, four.
Alright, it's go time. It's go time.
Come on, buddy. Come on, buddy.
Yes, it works!
Sorry!
That's my fault.
Yeah, yeah, I'm on it. Position four, uh, three.
Yeah! Go baby!
Oh, this is amazing! The wind in my...
cheat sheet!
Stop!
No!
Oh, Gosh! Oh, God!
Oh no!
Alright. Okay. You gotta kinda angle yourself!
Okay. No, no, no... Come back down towards me.
Come back down... Oww!
Yeah!
Come on...
Uh, no thanks. I'm good.
Not so fireproof on the inside, are you?
Here you go.
Everything we know about you guys is wrong.
Dad, you're back!
Gobber's not here, so...
I know.
I came looking for you.
You did?   You've been keeping secrets.
I have?
Just how long did you think you could hide it from me?
I... I don't know what you...
Nothing happens on this island, without me hearing about it.
Oh?
So, lets talk... about that dragon
Oh Gods...
Dad, I'm so sorry. I...
I was going to tell you, I just didn't know how to uh...
You... you're not upset?   What? I was hoping for this!
Ah, you were?   And believe me...
It only gets better. Just wait till you spill a Nadder's guts for the first time...
and mount your first Gronckle head on a spear.
What feeling! You really had me going there, son.
All those years of the worst Viking Berk has ever seen.
Odin, it was rough. I almost gave up on you.
And all the while you were holding out on me.
Oh, Thor almighty!
With you doing so well in the ring...
we finally have something to talk about.
I uh, I brought you something...
to keep you safe in the ring.
Wow, thanks.
Your mother would wanted you to have it.
It's half of her breast plate.
Matching set. Keeps her... Keeps her close, you know.
Wear it proudly. You deserve it.
You've held your end of the deal.
I should really get to bed.
Yes, good, okay, good talk.   Yeah...
I'll see you back at the house. Great. Thanks for stopping by and...
the uh... breast hat.   I hope you like the, umm... the hat.
Well, good night.
Stay out of my way. I'm winning this thing!
Good. Please. By all means.
This time! This time for sure!
No! No, sonofa half troll, rateating munch bucket...!
Wait! Wait.
So... later.
Oh, oh! Not so fast!   I'm kinda late for...
What! Late for what, exactly?
Okay, quiet down. The Elder has decided.
Boy, you've done it! You've done it, Hiccup!
You get to kill the dragon!
That's my boy!
Yeah! Yes, I can't wait. I am so...
leaving. We're Leaving.
Let's pack up.
Looks like you and me are taking a little vacation.
Forever.
Awww, man.
What the...? Uh, w... what are you doing here?
I want to know what's going on.
No one just get as good as you do.
Especially... you.
Start talking.   I... I...
Are you training with someone?
Training? I didn't...
It better not involve this.
I know, this looks really bad but you see, this is...
You're right. You're right. You're right. I... I'm through with the lies.
I've been making... outfits!
So, you got me. It's time everyone knew.
Drag me back. Go ahead. Here we go.
Oww. Why would you do that?
That's for the lies!
And that's... for everything else!
Oh man.
Get down!
Run! Run!
No! No! It's okay. It's okay. She's a friend.
You just scared him.
I scared him?
Who is him?
Astrid, Toothless. Toothless, Astrid.
Dut, da da... We're dead.
Woah, woah woah. Where do you think your going?
Oh, great Odin! Don't. Oh, this is...
Hiccup, get me down from here!
You have to give me a chance to explain.
I am not listening to anything you have to say!
Then I won't speak. Just let me show you.
Please, Astrid.
Now get me down!
Toothless, down. Gently.
See, nothing to be afraid of.
Toothless?
What is wrong with you? Bad dragon!
He's uh, he's not usually like this.
Oh, no!
Toothless, what are you doing? We need her to like us!
And now he's spinning!
Thank you for nothing you useless reptile!
Okay, I am sorry, I'm sorry. Just get me off of this thing.
Alright, I admit it. This is pretty cool.
It's amazing. He's amazing.
So what now?
Hiccup, your final exam is tomorrow!
You know your gonna have to kill a...
kill a dragon...
Don't remind me.
Toothless, what happening?
Whoa, what is it?
Get down!
What's going on?   I don't know.
Toothless, you gotta get us out of here, bud.
It looks like they're hauling in their kill.
What does that make us?
What my dad wouldn't give to find this.
Oh, it's satisfying to know that all of our food has been dumped down a hole.
They're not eating any of it.
What... was that?
Alright, bud, we gotta get out of here. Now!
No, no, it totally makes sense. It's like a giant beehive.
They're the workers, and that's their queen.
It controls them. Let's find your dad.
No, no.
No. Not yet. They'll kill Toothless.
Astrid, we have to think this through, carefully.
Hiccup, we just discovered the dragon's nest.
The thing we've been after since Vikings first sailed here.
And you want to keep it secret?
To protect your pet, dragon? Are you serious?
Yes.
Okay. Then what do we do?
Just give me until tomorrow. I'll figure something out.
Okay...
That's for kidnapping me.
That's for... everything else.
What are you looking at?
Well, I can show my face in public again.
If someone had told me that in a few short weeks
Hiccup will go from... well being... uh... Hiccup,
to placing first in dragon training.
Well, I would have tied him to a mast and shipped him off. For fear he'd gone mad.
And you know it.
But, here we are.
And no ones more surprised or more proud than I am.
Today my boy becomes a Viking!
Today he becomes one of us!
Be careful with that dragon.
It's not the dragon I'm worried about.
What are you going to do?
Put an end to this.
I have to try.
Astrid, if something goes wrong, just make sure they don't find Toothless.
I will, just promise me it won't go wrong.
It's time, Hiccup.
Knock 'em dead.
I'd have gone for the hammer.
I'm ready.
Go on Hiccup, give it to him!
What is he doing?
It's okay, it's okay.
I'm not one of them.
What's he thinking?
Stop the fight!
No! I need you all to see this.
They're not what we think they are.
We don't have to kill them.
I said stop the fight!
Out of my way!
Hiccup!
This way!
Night Fury!
Alright, Toothless. Go! Get out of here.
Go, go!
No, dad! Dad, he won't hurt you!
Toothless, stop!
No. No!
Get him!
No, no, please. Just don't hurt him
Please. Don't hurt him
Put it with the others.
I should have known.
I should have seen the signs.
Dad?   We had a deal!
I know! We did, but that was before I... Oh, it's all so messed up.
So everything in that ring... A trick? A lie?
I screwed up. I should have told you before now.
Take this out on me, be mad at me, but please, just don't hurt Toothless.
The dragon? That's what you're worried about?
Not the people you almost killed?
He was just protecting me! He's not dangerous.
They've killed hundreds of us!
And we've killed thousands of them. They defend themselves, that's all.
They raid us because they have to.
If they don't bring enough food back, they'll be eaten themselves.
There's something else on their island, dad. It's a dragonlike...
Their island? So, you've been to the nest?
Did I say nest?   How did you find it?
No, no, I didn't. Toothless did. Only a dragon can find the island.
No, no, dad, no please. It's not what you think.
You don't know what your up against. It's like nothing you've ever seen.
Dad, please, I promise you. You can't win this one!
Dad, no!
For once in your life, would you please just listen to me!
You've thrown your lot in with them.
You're not a Viking.
You're not my son!
Ready the ships!
Set sail!
We head for Hell Hounds gate.
Lead us home, devil.
It's a mess. You must feel horrible.
You've lost everything. Your father, your tribe, your best friend.
Thank you for summing that up.
Why couldn't I've killed that dragon, when I found him the woods?
Would've been better for everyone.
Yep, the rest of us would have done it.
So, why didn't you?
Why didn't you?
I don't know. I couldn't.
That's not an answer.   Why is this so important to you all of a sudden?
Because I want to remember what you say, right now.
Ah, for the love of... I was coward, I was weak.
I wouldn't kill a dragon!
You said wouldn't that time?
Whatever, I wouldn't!
300 years and I'm the first Viking who wouldn't kill a dragon.
First to ride one though.
So?
I wouldn't kill him because he looked as frightened as I was.
I looked at him and I saw myself.
I bet he's really frightened now.
What are you gonna do about it?
Probably something stupid.
Good, but you've already done that.
Then something crazy!
That's more like it.
Sound your positions! Stay within earshot.
Listen, Stoick, I was overhearing some of the men just now and well, you know...
some of them are wondering what it is we're up to here?
Not me of course. I know you are always the man with the plan.
But some, not me, are wondering if there is in fact a plan at all...
and what it might be?
Find the nest and take it.
Of course. Send them running. The old Viking fallback. Nice and simple.
Step aside.
Head to port.
If you're planning on getting eaten, I'd definitely go with the Gronckle.
You were wise to seek help from the world's most deadly weapon.
It's me.
I love this plan!   I didn't...
You're crazy. I like that.
So, what is the plan?
That's not very encouraging.
Oh, I was wondering where that went.
Stay low, and ready your weapons.
We're here.
Wait, what are you... ?!
It's okay... It's okay.
Where are you going?
You're gonna need something to help you hold on.
When we crack this mountain open, all hell is gonna break loose.
In my undies. Good thing I brought extras.
No matter how this ends, it ends today.
Is that it?
We've done it!
This isn't over!
Form your ranks. Pull together!
Get clear!
Beards of Thor...! What is that?
Odin, help us!
Catapults!   Fire!
Get to the ships!   No, nooo!
Not that one...   I was a fool.
Lead the men to the far side of the island.
Gobber, go with the men.
I think I'll stay, just in case you're thinking of doing something crazy.
I can buy them a few minutes if I give that thing something to hunt for.
Then I can double that time.
Here!   Oh, no. Here!
Fight me!   No, me!
Ruff, Tuff, watch your backs!
Move, Fishlegs!
Look at us! We're on dragons! We're on dragons! All of us!
Every bit the bullheaded stubborn Viking you ever were.
Fishlegs, break it down!   Okay.
Heavily armored skull and tail made for bashing and crushing. Steer clear of both.
Small eyes, large nostrils. Relies on hearing and smell.
Okay, Lout, Legs, hang in its blind spot. Make some noise. Keep it confused.
Ruff, Tuff, find out if it has a shot limit. Make it mad.
That's my specialty!   Since when?
Everyone knows I'm more irritating, see.
Just do what I told you. I'll be back as soon as I can.
Don't worry! We got it covered!
Yeah!
Fool!   Butto!
Bye, ya Grendel!
Um, this thing doesn't have a blind spot!
There!
Go help the others!
Okay, hold on. Hold on.
It's working!   Yeah, it's working!
I've lost power on the Gronckle! Snotlout, do something!
I'm okay!
Less okay.
I can't miss! What's wrong, buddy? You got something in your eye?
Yeah, you're the Viking!
Woah!
Dad?
You got it, buddy!
Hiccup!
I'm sorry...
for... for everything.
Yeah... me too.
You don't have to go up there.
We're Vikings. It's an occupational hazard...
I'm proud to call you my son.
Thanks, Dad.
He's up!
Get Snotlout outta there!
I'm on it!   I'm on it first!
Hey, let me drive!
Don't push me!   I'll push your teeth out!
You know, I can't believe that worked.
Night Fury!   Get down!
Did you get her?
Go!
This thing has wings. Okay, let's see if it can use them!
You think that did it?
Well, he can fly.
Okay, Toothless, time to disappear! Come on, bud!
Here it comes!
Watch out!
Okay, time's up. Let's see if this works.
Come on! Is that the best you can do?
Stay with me, buddy. We're good. Just a little bit longer.
Hold, Toothless. Now!
No... No!
Hiccup! Hiccup!
Son!
Hiccup!
Oh son!
I did this.
I'm s... I'm so sorry.
Hiccup!
He's alive! You brought him back alive!
Thank you... for saving my son.
Well, you know, most of him.
Hey, Toothless.
Happy to see you too, buddy.
Aawww, what... uh... I'm... in my house
You're in my house.
Does my dad know you're here?
Uh, what, oh, okay... okay.
Toothless, no. Toothless! Aw, come on.
Okay. Thanks, bud.
Toothless, stay here.
C'mon guys. Get ready! Hold on tight. Here we go!
What?
I knew it. I'm dead.
No, but you give it your best shot.
So, what do you think?
Hey look, it's Hiccup!
Hiccup!
It turns out, all we needed was a little more of... this.
You just gestured to all of me?
Well, most of you. That bit's my handiwork.
With a little Hiccup flare thrown in. You think that'll do?
I might make a few tweaks.
That's... for scaring me.
What... what, is it always going to be this way? Because...
I could get used to it.
Welcome home.
Night Fury!   Get down!
You ready?
This is Berk...
It snows nine months of the year and hails the other three.
Any food that grows here is tough and tasteless.
The people that grow here are even more so.
The only upsides are the pets.
While other places have ponies or parrots...
We have...
Dragons.